<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
    
    <properties>
        <author email="yveszoundi.AT.users.DOT.sf.DOT.net">Yves Zoundi</author>
        <title>Features</title>        
    </properties> 
    
    <body>  
        
        <section name = "Features"> 
            <subsection name = "Modularity">
                <p>XPontus is now built on top of a plugin framework to allow a modular development. Most of XPontus features are provided as plugins.</p>
            </subsection>
             <subsection name= "Code completion">
                 <p>For general XML files code completion is built on the fly when a DTD or schema is associated to the document. XSL completion is provided using a DTD embedded in the XML code completion plugin.</p>
                <p>For HTML files, an embedded DTD is used to create the code completion database.</p> 
            </subsection>
            <subsection name= "XPath support">
                <p>XPath 1.0 and 2.0 are supported.</p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name= "Syntax highlighting">
               <p>Syntax coloring is enabled for XML and HTML related files</p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name = "XSL transformations">
                <p>Like in the previous versions, XSL transformations are available(PDF, HTML, XML, SVG, TEXT).</p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name= "Validation"> 
                <ul>
                    <li>The Simple validation plugin can validate an opened document only</li>
                    <li>The Batch XML validation can accept a list of files and/or directories and validate them based on some file extensions patterns(*.xml, *.xsl)</li>                     
                    <li>he External schema validation plugin validates a file against an external schema(ie when the document has no associated schema)</li>
                </ul>
            </subsection> 
            <subsection name="Code structure browser">
                <p>XPontus can display the hierarchic structure of XML and HTML files</p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Code indentation">
                <p>Code indentation is available for XML and HTML files.</p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name = "File system abstractions">
                <p>XPontus will be able to use file system abstraction which means that a FTP file and a local file will be look all the same to the application.</p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name = "Schema generation/conversion">
                <p>The software can generate DTDS, XML schemas, Relax NG grammars from XML files.</p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name ="Documentation generator">
                <p>XPontus features 2 types of documentation generators:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>an XML schema documentation generator</li>
                    <li>a DTD documentation generator</li> 
                </ul>
            </subsection> 
            <subsection name = "Multiple installers">
                <p>Installers are available for Windows, Linux(Debian/Ubuntu, Suse/Fedora, Slackware), Unix, FreeBSD, Mac OS. There is also a cross platform installer</p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name = "Platform interoperability">
                <p>As XPontus is written Java, it runs on most platforms such as Windows, Linux/Unix, FreeBSD, MacOS.</p>
            </subsection>
        </section>  
    </body>
</document>
