<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">


<!--
  Copyright 2002-2005 The Apache Software Foundation or its licensors,
  as applicable.

  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at

      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<document>
	<header>
		<title>Welcome to XPontus XML Editor website</title>		
		<meta name="keywords">XML Editor, XML, XSLT, XML IDE, DTD, XSLT Editor, XSL Editor, XPontus XML Editor, Java based XML Editor</meta>
		<meta name="description">XPontus XML Editor homepage</meta>
		<meta name="robots">index, follow</meta>
	</header>
	
	<body>
		<section id="overview">
			<title>Overview</title>
			<p>XPontus is a free java based XML editor designed towards text editing. It aims to provide a free alternative to commercial XML Editors.</p>
			<p>As XPontus is written in Java it is available for all java enabled operating systems. It has been reported to run correctly on Linux, Windows, Mac OS X, Solaris and FreeBSD. There are many installers for platform convenience.</p>
                        <p>The software is distributed under the GNU GPL License. </p>
                        <p><a href="screenshots.html"><img title = "Screenshots" alt = "Screenshots" src = "images/thumb.png"/></a></p>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Why, When XPontus?</title>
			<p>2 years ago i was looking for a free XML Editor. I discovered a commercial XML Editor
				called <a class="fork" href="http://oxygenxml.com">Oxygen XML</a> which wasn't that popular and I liked it. Good and intuitive commercial XML editors are rather expensive. Typically when you buy an XML Editor, you pay for the support and the maintenance packs every year.</p>
			<p>I decided to create a free XML editor as I work a lot with XML related technologies.</p>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>The programming language choice</title>
			<p>One of the main design goal was to make the software available to many platforms, so I choose java. I also work as a programmer analyst and java is the primary development language.</p>
			<p>It could have been written in any object oriented language easily.</p>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How i decided to design XPontus XML Editor architecture, to code ...</title>
			<p>I needed to use a kind of MVC architecture to maintain easily the application. I use <a class="fork" href="http://springframework.org">Spring</a> as object container which configures actions,
				toolbar and the menubar from a XML file.</p>
			<p>Data bindings and user settings storage are easier to deal with when using <a href="http://xstream.codehaus.org/" class="fork">XStream</a> and <a href="https://binding.dev.java.net/" class="fork">JGoodies bindings</a>.</p>
			<p>I followed some patterns such as singleton pattern, observer pattern,etc.</p>
			<p>I am using <a href = "http://netbeans.org" class = "fork">Netbeans</a> to code most of the gui because it doesn't really affect the code performance. When i first started i was using a kind of notepad but it was taking me too much time to type :-)</p>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>
