<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
    
    <properties>
        <author email="yveszoundi AT users DOT sf DOT net">Yves Zoundi</author>
        <title>Homepage</title>        
    </properties>
     
    
    <body> 
       <section name = "Information">
            <p>I plan to release a snapshot version of XPontus 1.0.0-pre1 in early 2008. It will a Java Web Start only release with as less bugs as possible. It will allow me to get a quick feedback before the official release.</p>
        </section>
        
        <section name ="Overview">
            <p>XPontus XML Editor is a simple XML Editor with lots of features. It aims to become "the" free alternative to
            commercial XML IDES such as XMLSPy or Oxygen XML Editor, or Exchanger XML Editor.</p>
            <p>I focus the development on simplicity and speed. I try to optimize the code for low specs pcs. This is why most features will be available as modules.
            The editor will never become a monster beast with 100mb to download at least for now :-0.</p> 
        </section>
        
        <section name = "About the new branch">
            <p>This is a complete rewrite of the previous beta and release candidates. Lots of new features
                were requested again and again. It was very difficult to add new features in a modular 
                manner without touching the code base. I learned a lot from my first coding attempts 
                and I feel more experienced now. I hope that the brand new version will be great.
            The latest news about XPontus development can be found on my <a target = "_blank" href = "http://yveszoundi.blogspot.com">blog</a>.</p>
        </section> 
        
        <section name ="Features">
            <p>XPontus tries to provide you the features you would expect in a real XML IDE in a familiar and conviviable manner.</p>
            <p>I work on the usability and look at other applications to inspire myself when I design the application. So when
            you choose to use XPontus XML Editor, you are not completely lost. </p>
            <p>XPontus is not just an XML Editor no more, it is becoming a framework with pluggable modules. The plugin framework used
            to create XPontus plugins is <a target = "_blank" href = "http://jpf.sf.net">JPF</a>.</p>
        </section>
        
    </body>
</document>
